This is a bald eagle.
He's a legendary hunter who has mastered
the art of catching fish.
He also happens to hold the secrets to
memorising scripture.
Let's imagine us Christians are bald
eagles, and the verses we want to
memorise are tasty fish just waiting to
be poached.
The eagle does these 3 things to ensure
his hunt has the best chance of success.
So today we'll learn how to do the same.
As someone who's been reading the Bible
for almost 23 years, I couldn't stand the
constant reading, covering, reciting and
writing out verses of the traditional
memorisation method.
So I simply changed the strategy.
This one requires no commitment and no
repetition, and you can memorise not only
verses, but entire books of the Bible.
And hey, if you find this video useful or
you just like bald eagles, why not
subscribe, it really helps out.
Now, if anything like me, you've probably
got a handful of verses that you really
love and you want to be able to recite
from memory.
Well, unfortunately with this method
you're going to get way more value than
just that.
We're going to analyse the Eagles hunt in
3 stages.
The 1st stage is surveying the river.
Before diving head 1st into an icy cold
river with no taste of fish inside.
The eagle must 1st survey the river from
above and plan out his attack.
Let's say you want to memorise Ephesians
2 verse 8.
A great choice.
But let's not dive headfirst like this
guy.
We need to plan our attack first.
Think of the river like a book you're
reading.
And the fish within it, like the verses
you want to remember.
This method works with every single book
in the Bible, and you only ever need to
do this stage, once per book.
Our goal is to get an eagle's perspective
on the book.
And you can do that by answering these 3
questions.
Who wrote it and when?
Who were the original audience?
What is the purpose of the book?
Or why does it exist?
Feel free to Google these answers than to
write them down somewhere.
This is your reconnaissance mission
surveying the river for a successful
hunt.
Let's answer them for the book of
Ephesians.
Question number one.
Paul was the author sometime during his
ministry after Jesus' resurrection.
Question number two, the Ephesian Church
is the audience, a large multicultural
gathering pastored by Paul's protégé
Timothy, and question number three.
The main purpose of Ephesians was to
encourage the early Christians to be
united together under Christ, both Jews
and Gentiles.
Now we've created a lens to view this
book through.
We know some basic information that is
essential in helping our memory process
or in this case, our hunt.
The river has been scoped out, so it's
time to now identify the big fish.
Our eagle friend knew this river boasted
some pretty tasty fish, just like how you
knew the book of Ephesians had this
banger of a verse in it.
But we have a problem.
We still need to memorise it.
The Ephesians 28 fish is still swimming
away with unsuspecting bliss.
So we've studied the river.
Let's now study the target.
This is the part of the process I call
mapping out your Bible.
For this, you need a physical Bible and
one that you're willing to write in.
Now hang on, don't panic.
You'll be fine.
First, find and mark each chapter in the
book.
When you mark them, take note of which
column they're in, and roughly how far
down they are.
Remembering the physical location of
these numbers will be really important as
we progress.
Think of these chapters like runs of a
river, broken up by some descending
rapids.
Each one flows into the next, so knowing
what came before is essential for
catching the big trout.
Next, find where your target fish likes
to swim.
In our case, our Ephesians 2 8 fish
happens to be in the 2nd run of the river
chapter 2.
But there's a lot of space in that
section.
So where can we expect to find this big
guy?
Well, Ephesians 2 has 22 verses.
So we know that verse 8 will be in the
1st half of the river's run.
If you're a visual person sketching out a
river diagram like this might be helpful
to you.
So you've physically mapped out your
Bible, identifying where the chapters
start and end, and you've also identified
where our verse fits within the chapter.
Now you want to mark the memory verse and
do your absolute best to remember its
physical position on the page.
This will be very important in our final
step, which is following the current.
It's almost time for us to swoop in for
that sweet catch, but the fish is in a
current that continues all throughout the
river.
We need to find out what the current is
and where our fish is within it.
This is the most important step for
memorising scripture.
Most books of the Bible have a current
flowing through it, either a theme, a
story, an argument, or something else.
In Ephesians one, Paul talks a lot about
our adoption into God's family.
Ah, it makes more sense now.
We learned that Paul's purpose in stage
one was to encourage the early Christians
to be united together under Christ.
So in his intro, he's making the case
that Jews and Gentiles are adopted into
the same family.
So division should stop.
Pretty smart.
In chapter 2, he continues his argument
using the analogy of death and life to
address one of the 1st problems causing
division, boasting.
This step takes a little more time and
will be different for every book, but
there's always a current.
We just need to find them.
So Ephesians 28 sits at the end of Paul's
argument.
It is by grace you have been saved
through faith.
And this is not of yourselves, it is a
gift of God.
Makes sense why the fish is in this
particular area of the river now. because
the current has taken it now.
Side note, the books like Proverbs and
Psalms may be the hardest to find
currents in.
As lots of verses are one-liners or
separate chapters, but they have been
assembled in a certain way.
So keep looking for that flow.
Notice I haven't talked once about
reciting or recalling the exact words of
the verse.
Because each translation differs slightly
from one another.
I found it far more effective to memorise
the purpose and context behind the verse
because it seems to stick in our brains a
little better than just wrote
repetition.
So next time someone's trying to remember
that verse about grace and boasting.
You'll remember the book of Ephesians.
Then you'll recall the mapping of your
Bible, physical location of the chapters
and your brain will naturally drift down
the current until you reach the verse.
And when you recite it, it won't be
perfect.
But it's far better to memorise meaning
without words than words without meaning.